Ryan McMurray

4000 Pleasant Ridge Rd, Apt. M47 • Knoxville, TN 37912 • (276) 492-0146 • rmcmurr5@vols.utk.edu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

MSBA candidate with strong background in statistics. Gained experience by interning for Eastman Chemical Company and HCA. Introduced machine learning tactics to investigate financial records. Experienced in communicating analytical information to all audiences. Relevant coursework: Regression, Decision Optimization, Text Mining and Data Mining.

EDUCATION

University of Tennessee, Haslam College of Business, Knoxville, TN

Master of Science in Business Analytics, GPA 3.6

December 2018

Brigham Young University, Provo, UT

BS, Statistics, Minor: Mathematics, GPA 3.33

December 2016

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hospital Corporation of America, Nashville, TN

IS Development Intern

May 2018 - August 2018

- Wrote SQL queries to join multiple datasets in Teradata SQL Assistant to perform appropriate analysis
- Designed an anomaly detection model using a KNN approach that helped accelerate internal audit with reviewing potentially anomalous financial entries
- Brought insights to business partners and leadership, sharing key findings through machine learning and statistics and creating standard reports for stakeholders to make better decisions

Eastman Chemical Company, Kingsport, TN

Legal Analyst Intern

May 2015 – August 2015

- Built predictive models to analyze injury reports, accidental release data, and corporate travel expenses to create a safer, more efficient work environment
- Analyzed statistics currently being implemented in federal permits
- Created a survey to collect data about corporate travel expenses and analyzed with text mining techniques
- Presented technical material and aimed to provide new angles of perspective

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Haslam College of Business, University of Tennessee

Graduate Teaching Assistant

August 2017 - May 2018

- Engaged with upperclassmen students to better grasp challenging concepts
- Instructed 25 students on a one-on-one basis to provide customized assistance
- Graded and gave timely feedback to more than 75 students

Statistics Department, Brigham Young University

January 2015 – December 2016

Teacher Assistant

- Tutored students from non-statistical backgrounds to better understand course material
- Taught a weekly lab for students to come and receive help for questions and general review of challenging topics

SKILLS

Computer: R, Python, SAS, JMP, Tableau, Excel, Ampl

Language: Fluent Spanish

Interests: Enjoy traveling, playing soccer, frisbee, racquetball, snowboarding, marathon running

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT AND LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES

Capstone Project Manager	2018-present
 Chosen by the Business Analytics faculty to lead a consulting team for a project with a Fortune 	
500 company	
Provo Youth Mentoring	2014 - 2016
 Volunteered at weekly activities for underprivileged sixth graders 	
Full-Time Volunteer (Argentina), The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints	2011 - 2013
 Instructed and taught various groups of other volunteers 	
 Prepared lessons to be taught in the Spanish language 	
Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America	2004 - 2010